<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">

    
     <a name="volume1"></a><h4>Purpose</h4>

    <p>The CH eTransition of Care (CH eTOC) Implementation Guide defines the content of a referral from a GP to the hospital, to a specialist,
    from one hispital to another etc.
    </p>

    <p>CH eTOC is intended for use in directional communiation as well as for the use in the SWISS EPR.
    </p>  

  <a name="volume1"></a><h4>Foundation</h4>
    
    <p>This Implementation Guide uses FHIR defined resources. For details on HL7 FHIR R4 see <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/r4">http://hl7.org/fhir/r4</a>
    </p>

    <p>Because the Implementation Guide relies heavily on the FHIR Resources Questionnaire and QuestionnaireResponse, forms are addressed here as Questionnaires.
    </p>
    
    <p>This Implementation Guide is derived from the Order &amp; Referral by Form (ORF) Implementation Guide  
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-orf/index.html">CH-ORF</a> which relies on HL7 Structured Data Capture Implementation Guide, see
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/HL7/sdc/">SDC IG</a> and uses the Swiss Core Profiles, see 
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-core/index.html">CH Core</a>
    </p>

    <p>Applications claiming for conformance with the CH eTOC Implementation Guide shall:
    </p>

        <ul>
            <li>Render (and in case of the Questionnaire filler allow for data entry) all elements of a questionnaire marked as 
            "CH-mandatoy" in the user interface (e.g. on screen, in print). Grouping of items and the order of items within shall be adequately
            reproduced according to the Questionnaire.</li>
            <li>Be able to process all items denoted as "CH-mandatoy".</li>

        </ul>
   
   <p>Currently, some items are marked as "MUST SUPPORT". This is due to the fact, that this IG is derived partly from the 
   International Patient Summary (IPS). It is envisaged, that CH eTOC shall support all MUST SUPORT Items of IPS in
   a future version. For the time now, this is not the case; the first DSTU requests only support of "CH-mandatoy" items: these are mainly free text entries. 
    </p>

    <p>As a consequence of this decision, the first version of CH eTOC does not claim to be confromant to IPS.
    </p>

    <p>Vendors of applications with Questionnaire Filler/Questionnaire Receiver Actors are strongly recommended to implement
    interfaces to other applications (such as HIS and PACS) for all MUST SUPPORT items.
    </p>
    
    <p> Actors, transcations and security considerations are covered in the corresponding sections of 
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-orf/index.html">CH-ORF</a>
    </p>

    <a name="volume3"></a><h4>Terminology</h4>

    <p>This section is not yet written.
    </p> 

</div>