<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">


    <p>This Implementation Guide uses FHIR defined resources – Composition Resource, Questionnaire Resource,
    QuestionnaireResponse Resource, Patient Resource, PractitionerRole Resource, Practitioner Resource, Organization Resource, ServiceRequest Resource and Bundle Resource from
    FHIR R4. For details on HL7 FHIR R4 see <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/r4">http://hl7.org/fhir/r4</a>.
    </p>
    <p>The CH Electronic Transition of Care (CH eTOC) Implementation Guide describes how forms for eReferrals from one healthcare provider to another (e.g. paratctioner to hospital, hospital to hospital etc.), 
    shall be defined, deployed and used in order to achieve a syntactical and semantically consistent cross enterprise information exchange.
    </p>
    <p>The Implementation Guide relies on FHIR e.g. the questionnaire resource. Because the Implementation Guide relies heavily on the FHIR Resources Questionnaire and
    QuestionnaireResponse, forms are addressed here as Questionnaires.
    </p>
    <p>This Implementation Guide is derived from the Order &amp; Referral by Form (ORF) Implementation Guide  
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/ehealthsuisse/ch-orf/">CH-ORF</a> which relies on HL7 Structured Data Capture Implementation Guide, see
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/HL7/sdc/">SDC IG</a> and uses the Swiss Core Profiles, see 
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-core/index.html">CH Core</a>.
    </p>
    <p>Applications claiming for conformance with the eTOC Implementation Guide shall:
    </p>
    <ul>
        <li>Render (and in case of the Questionnaire filler allow for data entry) all elements of a questionnaire in the
        user interface (e.g. on screen, in print). Grouping of items and the order of items within shall be adequately
        reproduced according to the Questionnaire.</li>
        <li>Be able to process all MUST SUPPORT items.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Venders of applications with Questionnaire Filler/Questionnaire Receiver Actors are strongly recommended to implement
    interfaces to other applications (such as HIS and PACS) for all MUST SUPPORT items.
    <a name="volume1"></a><h3>Content Modules</h3>
    </p>
    <p>This Implementation Guide covers the content of CH eTOC based on CH-ORF. CH eTOC is intended for use in directional communication
    as well as for the use in the SWISS EPR.  
    </p>
   <p> Actors, transactions and security considerations are covered in the corresponding sections of 
      <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/ehealthsuisse/ch-orf/">CH-ORF</a>
    </p>
    <a name="volume3"></a><h4>Questionnaire Content</h4>
    <p>This section describes the content of a form. The following definitions apply:
    </p>
    <p>Request and responses consist of filled in questionnaires. Some elements of the questionnaire are generic 
        elements (such as author, data entry person, receiver etc. and are always present in a questionnaire compliant to
        the ORF Implementation Guide. In addition, a questionnaire will contain elements which are dependent on particular needs of 
        the addressed use cased. Those eleements are named Healthcare Domain Specific Elements.
    </p>
    <a name="volume1"></a><h4>Generic elements of a questionnaire</h4>
    <p>A questionnaire shall have a set of generice elements (e.g. author, data entry person, receiver etc. 
        <sup>&#91;Table 7&#93;</sup> lists the generic given elements:
    </p>
     <table>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <th><b>Name</b>
                </th>
                <th colspan="2"><b>Role taker</b>
                </th>
                <th><b>HL7 V3<br /> Equivalent</b>
                </th>
                <th><b>FHIR<br /> Representation</b>
                </th>
                <th><b>Comment</b>
                </th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th>
                </th>
                <th><b>Human</b>
                </th>
                <th><b>Organization</b>
                </th>
                <th>
                </th>
                <th>
                </th>
                <th>
                </th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Author
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>Author
                </td>
                <td>PractitionerRole
                </td>
                <td>The person/organization responsible for the form content.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Data Entry Person
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>DataEnterer
                </td>
                <td>PractitionerRole
                </td>
                <td>The person/organization who has typed/filled in the form content.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Urgent Notification Contact for this document
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>PrimaryInformationRecipient
                </td>
                <td>PractitionerRole
                </td>
                <td>An information recipient to notify for urgent matters (e.g. in a radiology service, the radiologist 
                    has to be called by phone right away at the time the doucment is received.)
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Urgent Notification Contact for the Response to this document
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>PrimaryInformationRecipient
                </td>
                <td>PractitionerRole
                </td>
                <td>
                    <p>An information recipient to notify for urgent matters about the response (e.g. in a clinical
                        setting, the referring doctor has to be called by phone right away at the time the images and
                        reports arrive).
                    </p>
                    <p>The Urgent Notification Contact for the Response can be specified already in the request. At the
                        time the response is written, this element shall be populated to the Urgent Notification Contact
                        element in the response.
                    </p>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Request Receiver
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>PractitionerRole
                </td>
                <td>Person/organization who receives the request.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Response Receiver
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>PractitionerRole
                </td>
                <td>Person/organization who receives the response.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Patient
                </td>
                <td>X
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>Patient
                </td>
                <td>The principle target of a particular form content is one patient (for obstetrical and neonatal use
                    cases see...).
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Precedent Document Id
                </td>
                <td>na
                </td>
                <td>na
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>This element provides a link to the preceding document in a thread (e.g. from a response to the
                    request).
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Date
                </td>
                <td>na
                </td>
                <td>na
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>Date, the document was created.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Priority
                </td>
                <td>na
                </td>
                <td>na
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>Order priority.
                </td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
    <p><sup>&#91;Table 7&#93;</sup> <i>Generic elements in Questionnaires compliant to the ORF Implementation Guide</i>
    </p>
    <a name="volume1"></a><h4>Healthcare domain specific elements of a questionnaire</h4>
     <table>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <th>Resource
                </th>
                <th>Description
                </th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>ServiceRequest
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
    <p>There may be the need to provide a linkage between a particular files or between a particular file and an imaging
        study (e.g. a link between a PDF-File containing a report and a DICOM study). Such links shall be expressed with
        a DocumentReference as follows:
    </p>
     <table>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <th>Resource
                </th>
                <th colspan="3">Elements
                </th>
                <th>Description
                </th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>DocumentReference
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>type
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>(e.g. LOINC 18748-4 for Diagnostic imaging Study)
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>content
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>attachment
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>Attachment
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>contentType
                </td>
                <td>Mime Type
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>data
                </td>
                <td>Data inline, base64ed (contains the file; e.g. a PDF-Report)
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>context
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>related
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>
                </td>
                <td>Reference (ImagingStudy)
                </td>
                <td>ImagingStudyResource provides StudyInstanceUID etc.
                </td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>

    <a name="volume1"></a><h4>FHIR Representation</h4>
    <p>For questions regarding the FHIR representations please refer to the corresponding section of 
      <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/ehealthsuisse/ch-orf/">CH-ORF</a>
    </p>
</div>
